<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aruba Installation And Configuration Guide on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aruba Installation And Configuration Guide on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Example Of How To Configure Scenario A Or B</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/management_network_configuration_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/management_network_configuration_example/</guid>
      <description>Example of How to Configure Scenario A or B This section provides an example of how to configure the management network.
Procedure   Create the Customer Access Network (CAN) VRF for Aruba.
sw# config sw# vrf CAN   Move the interfaces into CAN VRF.
If there is an existing CAN interface configuration, it will be deleted the interface is moved into the new VRF; it will have to be re-applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Management Network Functions</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/management_network_function_in_detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/management_network_function_in_detail/</guid>
      <description>System Management Network Functions The following is a description of the system management network functions:
  Edge - Any interactions with the Customer network or Internet
 Customer Jobs - Customer Access Network (CAN) User-facing cloud APIs  User Access Instances (UAIs)   Customer Administration - Customer Management Network (CMN)  Administrative Access to the system by Customer Admins Access from the system to external services:  Customer/Internet DNS LDAP authentication System installation and upgrade media (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vsx Isl Ha</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/mclag_isl_ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/mclag_isl_ha/</guid>
      <description>VSX: ISL HA The intent here is to showcase an inter-switch-link (ISL) link failover scenario where one of the two links between spine switches goes down, but ISL is still connected with single link.
The following image is a visualization of disconnected ISL link:
The following things are expected to be seen in this scenario:
 After disconnecting one ISL, the VSX functionality should not be affected A small percentage of packets will be dropped when disconnecting the cable where traffic is flowing; A sub second value is expected during this event When connecting back the cable, the hashing needs to be recalculated and some packets may be dropped during this event as well; A sub second value is expected during this event  Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vsx Mclag Link Ha</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/mclag_link_ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/mclag_link_ha/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check For Duplicate Ip Addresses</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/duplicate_ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/duplicate_ip/</guid>
      <description>Check for Duplicate IP Addresses It is common to get an IP address that is not the correct one. A sign of a duplicate IP address is seeing a DECLINE message from the client to the server.
For example:
10.40.0.0.337 &amp;gt; 10.42.0.58.67: BOOTP/DHCP, Request from b4:2e:99:be:1a:d3, length 301, hops 1, xid 0x9d1210d, Flags [none] Gateway-IP 10.252.0.2 Client-Ethernet-Address b4:2e:99:be:1a:d3 Vendor-rfc1048 Extensions Magic Cookie 0x63825363 DHCP-Message Option 53, length 1: Decline Client-ID Option 61, length 19: hardware-type 255, 99:be:1a:d3:00:01:00:01:26:c8:55:c3:b4:2e:99:be:1a:d3 Server-ID Option 54, length 4: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Exec Banners</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/exec_banner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/exec_banner/</guid>
      <description>Configure Exec Banners Exec banners are custom messages displayed to users attempting to connect to the management interfaces. Multiple lines of text can be stored using a custom delimiter to mark the end of message.
Configuration Commands Create a banner:
switch(config)# banner &amp;lt;motd|exec&amp;gt; DELIM Show commands to validate functionality:
switch# show banner &amp;lt;motd|exec&amp;gt; Example Output switch(config)# banner exec $ Enter a new banner, when you are done enter a new line containing only your chosen delimiter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Hostnames</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/hostname/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/hostname/</guid>
      <description>Configure Hostnames A hostname is a human-friendly name used to identify a device. An example of a hostname could be the name &amp;ldquo;Test.&amp;rdquo;
Configuration Commands Create a hostname:
switch(config)# hostname &amp;lt;NAME&amp;gt; Show commands to validate functionality:
switch# show hostname Example Output switch(config)# hostname switch-test switch-test# show hostname switch-test Expected Results  Administrators can configure the hostname The output of all show commands is correct  Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Internet Group Multicast Protocol (igmp)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/igmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/igmp/</guid>
      <description>Configure Internet Group Multicast Protocol (IGMP) The Internet Group Multicast Protocol (IGMP) is a communications protocol used by hosts and adjacent routers on IP networks to establish multicast group memberships. The host joins a multicast-group by sending a join request message towards the network router, and responds to queries sent from the network router by dispatching a join report.
General notes:
 In ArubaOS-CX igmp snooping is disabled by default IGMP v3 is used by default, supported configuration allows v2 and v3  Configuration Commands switch(config)# interface vlan 1 switch(config-if-vlan)# igmp Expected Results show ip igmp-snooping vlan 1 should show IGMP enabled on the VLAN, but no IGMP Querier set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Prioritization</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/initial_prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/initial_prioritization/</guid>
      <description>Initial Prioritization For most switches, the local-priority has eight levels (0-7). Zero is the lowest priority. The allowed maximum will vary per product family. Local priority is used to determine which queue a packet will use. There are multiple options to configure the local-priority:
 qos cos-map: Maps Class of Services (CoS) values from VLAN tags in incoming packets to specific local priorities qos dscp-map: Maps the DSCP from incoming packets to specific local priorities qos trust: Assumes incoming packets are marked correctly, and takes the local-priority from either the CoS or Differentiated Service Code-Points (DSCP) field of the packet, or ignores any values set on incoming packets and places the packets into the default local-priority queue if the none option is given  Configuration Commands Map incoming 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The intent for the this documentation is to help install and manage Aruba CX network devices in an HPE Cray EX system installation.
The HPE Cray recommended way of configuring the network is with the CANU tool. Thus, this guide will not go to into a level of detail of how to configure each switch with the CLI in the topology. However, it will provide examples of how to configure and use features generated by CANU to provide administrators with an easy way to customize their installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Features Used In The Management Network Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/key_features/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/key_features/</guid>
      <description>Key Features Used in the Management Network Configuration The following is a list of key features used in the management network configuration.
Feature List    Feature Notes Description     VSX MLAG  Layer 2 Redundancy, Allows the NCNs to be bonded so if one link fails they can continue to operate.   VSX  Layer 3 Redundancy, Allows one Spine switch/default gateway to fail and continue to work   Lacp fallback  Allows for LACP links to come up individually without LACP PDUs, used for PXE booting the NCNs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aggregation Group (lag)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/lag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/lag/</guid>
      <description>Link Aggregation Group (LAG) Link Aggregation allows you to assign multiple physical links to one logical link that functions as a single, higher-speed link providing dramatically increased bandwidth.
Configuration Commands Create and configure the LAG interface:
switch(config)# interface lag LAG switch(config-lag-if)# no shutdown switch(config-lag-if)# lacp mode active Associate member links with the LAG interface:
switch(config)# interface IFACE switch(config-if)# no shutdown switch(config-if)# lag LAG Show commands to validate functionality:
switch# show lacp &amp;lt;interfaces|aggregates|configuration&amp;gt; Example Output switch# show interface lag1 Aggregate-name lag1 Aggregated-interfaces : 1/1/1 1/1/4 Aggregation-key : 1 Aggregate mode : active Speed 0 Mb/s qos trust none qos queue-profile default qos schedule-profile default RX TX 409 input packets 0 input error 0 CRC/FCS 530 output packets 0 input error 0 collision 47808 bytes 0 dropped 56975 bytes 0 dropped switch# show lacp interfaces State abbreviations : A - Active P - Passive S - Short-timeout L - Long-timeout N - InSync O - OutofSync C - Collecting D - Distributing X - State m/c expired E - Default neighbor state Actor details of all interfaces: ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ Intf Aggregate Port Port State System-id System Aggr name id Priority Priority Key ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 1/1/1lag1 59 1 ALFOE 70:72:cf:4d:bb:53 65534 1 1/1/4lag1 41 1 ALFOE 70:72:cf:4d:bb:53 65534 1 Partner details of all interfaces: ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ Intf Aggregate Partner Port State System-id System Aggr name Port-id Priority Priority Key ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 1/1/1lag1 0 65534 PLFOEX 00:00:00:00:00:00 65534 0 1/1/4lag1 0 65534 PLFOEX 00:00:00:00:00:00 65534 0 switch# show lacp aggregates Aggregate-name : lag1 Aggregated-interfaces : 1/1/1 1/1/4 Heartbeat rate : slow Aggregate mode : active F - Aggregable I - Individual Expected Results  Administrators can create and configure a LAG Administrators can add ports to a LAG Administrators can configure a LAG interface  Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Layer Discovery Protocol (lldp)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/lldp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/lldp/</guid>
      <description>Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP) LLDP is used to advertise the device&amp;rsquo;s identity and abilities and read other devices connected to the same network.
 NOTE: LLDP is enabled by default.
 Configuration Commands Enable an interface to receive or transmit LLDP packets:
switch(config-if)# lldp &amp;lt;receive|transmit&amp;gt; Show commands to validate functionality:
switch# show lldp [local-device|neighbor-info|statistics] Example Output switch# show lldp configuration LLDP Global Configuration: LLDP Enabled :Yes LLDP Transmit Interval :30 LLDP Hold time Multiplier :4 LLDP Transmit Delay Interval:2 LLDP Reinit time Interval :2 Optional TLVs configured: Management Address Port description Port VLAN-ID System capabilities System description System name LLDP Port Configuration: Port Tx-Enabled Rx-Enabled 1/1/1 Yes Yes .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locator Led</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/locator_led/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/locator_led/</guid>
      <description>Locator LED The Locator LED is an LED in the front of the chassis that you can turn on or make flash. This is a handy feature when guiding someone to your switch during a &amp;ldquo;remote hands&amp;rdquo; situation, such as asking data center engineer to run a cable to your switch.
Configuration commands Enable LED:
switch# led locator &amp;lt;flashing|off|on&amp;gt; Show commands to validate functionality:
switch# show environment led Example output switch# show environment led Name State Status ----------------------------------- locator off ok switch# led locator flashing switch# show system led Name State Status ----------------------------------- locator flashing ok switch# led locator on switch# show system led Name State Status ----------------------------------- locator on ok switch# led locator off switch# show system led Name State Status ----------------------------------- locator off ok Expected results  The Locator LED should be in the off state The Locator LED is now flashing The show command shows the LED is in the flashing state The Locator LED is lit a solid color and it does not flash The show command shows the LED is in the on state The LED is no longer lit The show command shows the LED is in the off state  Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loopback Interface</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/loopback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/loopback/</guid>
      <description>Loopback Interface Loopbacks are essentially internal virtual interfaces. Loopback interfaces are not bound to a physical port and are used for device management and routing protocols.
Configuration Commands switch(config)# interface loopback LOOPBACK switch(config-loopback-if)# ip address IP-ADDR/&amp;lt;SUBNET|PREFIX&amp;gt; Example Output switch(config)# interface loopback 1 switch(config-loopback-if)# ip address 99.99.99.1/32 switch(config-loopback-if)# end switch# show run interface loopback1 interface loopback1 no shutdown ip address 99.99.99.1/32 exit switch# show ip interface loopback1 Interface loopback1 is up Admin state is up Hardware: Loopback IPv4 address 99.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Authentication</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/mac_auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/mac_auth/</guid>
      <description>MAC Authentication MAC Authentication (MAC Auth) is a method of authenticating devices for access to the network. The default mode of authentication is RADIUS, through which clients are authenticated by an external RADIUS server.
Configuration Commands Enter MAC Auth context:
switch(config)# aaa authentication port-access mac-auth Enable MAC Auth on all interfaces:
switch(config-macauth)# enable Configure MAC Auth MAC address format:
switch(config-macauth)# addr-format &amp;lt;no-delimiter|single-dash|multi-dash|multi-colon|no-delimiter Enable MAC Auth password:
switch(config-macauth)# password &amp;lt;plaintext|ciphertext&amp;gt; PASSWORD Configure mac-auth RADIUS authentication method:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Management Interface</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/management_interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/management_interface/</guid>
      <description>Management Interface The management interface can be used to gain remote management access to the switch. The management interface is accessible using the &amp;ldquo;mgmt&amp;rdquo; VRF and is separate from the data plane interfaces, which are in the &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; VRF.
Alternatively, a loopback interface can be configured to be used as management interface.
Address Mode Admin State Mac Address IPv4 address/subnet-mask Default gateway IPv4 IPv6 address/prefix IPv6 link local address/prefix: fe10::96f1:28ff:fe1d:a901/64 Default gateway IPv6 Primary Nameserver Secondary Nameserver : : 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Capabilities</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/bluetooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/bluetooth/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth Capabilities The Bluetooth feature allows Bluetooth enabled devices to connect to and manage the switch on a wireless Bluetooth Personal Area Network (PAN). The user needs a supported USB Bluetooth dongle and to enable both the USB port and Bluetooth on the switch to use this feature. Bluetooth and REST write permissions for Bluetooth clients are both enabled by default.
Configuration Commands Turn on the USB port:
switch# usb mount Enable Bluetooth:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) Basics</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/bgp_basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/bgp_basic/</guid>
      <description>Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) Basics &amp;ldquo;The primary function of a Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) speaking system is to exchange network reachability information with other BGP systems. This network reachability information includes information on the list of Autonomous Systems (ASes) that reachability information traverses. This information is sufficient for constructing a graph of AS connectivity for this reachability, from which routing loops may be pruned and, at the AS level, some policy decisions may be enforced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cable Diagnostics</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/cable_diagnostics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/cable_diagnostics/</guid>
      <description>Cable Diagnostics Use the cable-diagnostic feature to test cables in the event where there might be a bad copper cable.
 NOTE: This feature is only available on non-SFP copper ports.
 Procedure Enter diagnostics to open up the diagnostics menu:
switch# diagnostics Once done, the diagnostics command set is now available for use, and the cable-diagnostics command can be executed:
switch# diag cable-diagnostic &amp;lt;IFACE&amp;gt; Example output 6300# diagnostics &amp;lt;CR&amp;gt; 6300# diag ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check BGP And Metallb</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_bgp_and_metallb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_bgp_and_metallb/</guid>
      <description>Check BGP and MetalLB Use the following procedure to verify if the spine switches are available and that MetalLB peering to the spine switches via Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) is established.
Prerequisites Access to the spine switches is required.
Procedure   Log in to the spine switches.
  Check that MetalLB is peering to the spines via BGP.
Check both spines if they are available (powered up):
sw-spine# show ip bgp summary All the neighbors should be in the Established state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Current DHCP Leases</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_current_dhcp_leases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_current_dhcp_leases/</guid>
      <description>Check Current DHCP Leases Use the Kea API to retrieve data from the DHCP lease database.
Prerequisites An auth token is set up. If one has not been set up, log on to ncn-w001 or a worker/manager with kubectl and run the following:
export TOKEN=$(curl -s -k -S -d grant_type=client_credentials -d client_id=admin-client -d client_secret=`kubectl get secrets admin-client-auth -o jsonpath=&#39;{.data.client-secret}&#39; | base64 -d` https://api-gw-service-nmn.local/keycloak/realms/shasta/protocol/openid-connect/token | jq -r &#39;.access_token&#39;) Once an auth token is generated, these commands can be run on a worker or manager node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check DHCP Lease Is Getting Allocated</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_dhcp_lease_is_getting_allocated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_dhcp_lease_is_getting_allocated/</guid>
      <description>Check DHCP Lease is Getting Allocated Checking Check the Kea logs and verify that the DHCP lease is getting allocated.
ncn-mw# KEA_POD=$(kubectl get pods -n services -l app.kubernetes.io/name=cray-dhcp-kea -o custom-columns=:.metadata.name --no-headers) ncn-mw# echo &amp;#34;${KEA_POD}&amp;#34; ncn-mw# kubectl logs -n services pod/&amp;#34;${KEA_POD}&amp;#34; -c cray-dhcp-kea The following example shows that Kea is allocating a lease to 10.104.0.23. The lease must say DHCP4_LEASE_ALLOC; if it says DHCP4_LEASE_ADVERT, then there is likely a problem.
2021-04-21 00:13:05.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Kea DHCP Logs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_kea_dhcp_logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_kea_dhcp_logs/</guid>
      <description>Check KEA DHCP Logs Use this procedure to check the logs for a cray-dhcp-kea pod.
Procedure   Retrieve the pod name.
The pod name is required to check the logs for the pod in question.
kubectl logs -n services -l app.kubernetes.io/instance=cray-dhcp-kea -c cray-dhcp-kea Example output:
2020-08-03 21:47:50.580 INFO [kea-dhcp4.dhcpsrv/10] DHCPSRV_MEMFILE_LEASE_FILE_LOAD loading leases from file /cray-dhcp-kea-socket/dhcp4.leases 2020-08-03 21:47:50.580 INFO [kea-dhcp4.dhcpsrv/10] DHCPSRV_MEMFILE_LFC_SETUP setting up the Lease File Cleanup interval to 3600 sec 2020-08-03 21:47:50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check The Hardware State Manager (HSM)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_hsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/check_hsm/</guid>
      <description>Check the Hardware State Manager (HSM) The Hardware State Manager (HSM) has two important parts:
 System Layout Service (SLS): This is the &amp;ldquo;expected&amp;rdquo; state of the system (as populated by networks.yaml and other sources) State Manager Daemon (SMD): This is the &amp;ldquo;discovered&amp;rdquo; or active state of the system during runtime  Procedure   Check SLS.
ncn# curl -H &amp;#34;Authorization: Bearer ${TOKEN}&amp;#34; https://api-gw-service-nmn.local/apis/sls/v1/hardware | jq | less The output from SLS should look similar to the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifier Policies</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/classifier_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/classifier_policies/</guid>
      <description>Classifier Policies Classifier policies allow a network administrator to define sets of rules based on network traffic addressing or other header content and use these rules to restrict or alter the passage of traffic through the switch.
Choosing the rule criteria is called classification, and one such rule, or list, is called a policy.
Classification is achieved by creating a traffic class. There are three types of classes – MAC, IPv4, and IPv6 – which are each focused on relevant frame/packet characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Domain Name Service (DNS) Clients</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/dns-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/dns-client/</guid>
      <description>Configure Domain Name Service (DNS) Clients The Domain Name Service (DNS) translates domain and host names to and from IP addresses. A DNS client resolves hostnames to IP addresses by querying assigned DNS servers for the appropriate IP address.
Configuration Commands Configure the switch to resolve queries via a DNS server:
switch(config)# ip dns server-address IP-ADDR [vrf VRF] Configure a domain name:
switch(config)# ip dns domain-name NAME Show commands to validate functionality:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Domain Names</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/domain_name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/domain_name/</guid>
      <description>Configure Domain Names A domain name is a name to identify the person, group, or organization that controls the devices within an area. An example of a domain name could be us.cray.com.
Configuration Commands Create a domain name:
switch(config)# domain-name NAME Show commands to validate functionality:
switch# show domain-name Expected Results  Administrators can configure the domain name The output of all show commands is correct  Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Number Of DHCP Declines During A Node Boot</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/dhcp_decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/dhcp_decline/</guid>
      <description>Large Number of DHCP Declines During a Node Boot If something similar to the following is in the logs, this indicates an issue that an IP address being allocated is already being used and is not able to get the IP assigned to the device as previously set.
dracut-initqueue[1902]: wicked: eth0: Declining DHCPv4 lease with address 10.252.0.56 dracut-initqueue[1902]: wicked: eth0: Declining DHCPv4 lease with address 10.252.0.57 dracut-initqueue[1902]: wicked: eth0: Declining DHCPv4 lease with address 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verify Computes/UANs/application Nodes</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/compute_uan_application_nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/compute_uan_application_nodes/</guid>
      <description>Verify Computes/UANs/Application Nodes If the computes make it past PXE and go into the PXE shell, verify DNS and connectivity.
iPXE&amp;gt; dhcp Configuring (net0 98:03:9b:a8:60:88).................. No configuration methods succeeded (http://ipxe.org/040ee186) Configuring (net1 b4:2e:99:be:1a:37)...... ok Procedure   Verify DNS:
iPXE&amp;gt; show dns Example output:
net1.dhcp/dns:ipv4 = 10.92.100.225   Verify connectivity:
iPXE&amp;gt; nslookup address api-gw-service-nmn.local iPXE&amp;gt; echo ${address} 10.92.100.71   Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.1x</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/8021x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/8021x/</guid>
      <description>802.1X IEEE 802.1X is an IEEE standard for port-based network access control (PNAC). This standard provides an authentication mechanism to devices wishing to attach to a LAN or WLAN. IEEE 802.1X defines the encapsulation of the Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP) over IEEE 802, which is known as EAP over LAN (EAPOL).
 NOTE: Port security is a feature of &amp;ldquo;edge&amp;rdquo; switches such as 63/6400, and it is not available on 83xx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Lists (ACLs)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/acl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/acl/</guid>
      <description>Access Control Lists (ACLs) ACLs are used to help improve network performance and restrict network usage by creating policies to eliminate unwanted IP traffic by filtering packets where they enter the switch on layer 2 and layer 3 interfaces. An ACL is an ordered list of one or more access control list entries (ACEs) prioritized by sequence number. An incoming packet is matched sequentially against each entry in an ACL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Address Resolution Protocol (arp)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/arp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/arp/</guid>
      <description>Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) ARP is commonly used for mapping IPv4 addresses to MAC addresses.
Procedure   Configure static ARP on an interface.
switch(config-if)# arp ipv4 IP-ADDR mac MAC-ADDR   Show commands to validate functionality: .
switch# show arp   Expected Results  Administrators are able to ping the connected device Administrators can view the ARP entries  Back to Index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup A Switch Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/aruba/backup/</guid>
      <description>Backup a Switch Configuration Copies the running configuration or the startup configuration to a remote location as a file. The configuration can be exported to a file of either type CLI or type JSON format. The &amp;lt;VRF-NAME&amp;gt; is used for the configuration of interfaces on a particular VRF.
Procedure Create a copy of a running configuration or the startup configuration using the following command:
copy {running-config | startup-config} &amp;lt;REMOTE-URL&amp;gt; {cli | json} [vrf &amp;lt;VRF-NAME&amp;gt;] The parameters/syntax of the copy command are described below:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
